Connor Cyphers

19747 Willowdale Place, Ashburn, VA 20147

Phone: 703-431-8342 email: color.red@tutanota.com

SKILLS

- · Microsoft Office Suite
- Structured Query Language (SQL) programming
- Foreign language skills: Chinese Intermediate level, Spanish Intermediate/advanced level. Also completed language coursework in Arabic, French and German.

CERTIFICATIONS

• Google IT Support Professional Certification

EXPERIENCE

Best Buy Geek Squad

Geek Squad Agent (10/2020-present)

Responsible for installing home theater equipment and other electronic devices in client's homes. Provided troubleshooting of home networks and other PC problems.

Fast Editing Solutions, Beijing, China

Editor (6/2016 – present)

Editing and polishing of essays, documents, school applications, and webpages for a variety of clients including students, business owners and others.

Beile English School, Beijing, China

Head Foreign Instructor (1/2017 - 1/2019)

Responsible for management, scheduling and training of the school's Foreign Instructor department. Work collaboratively with the Vice Principle and Academic Department leadership to address needs of the school and define and implement strategies to increase profitability.

- Organized and executed school marketing events for parents and students to recruit new students to the school.
- Served as the initial instructor at a new school location and played a primary role in recruiting the initial student body. Grew school enrollment from zero students to the current enrollment of 500 students in two years.

VIPKID English, Beijing, China

Curriculum Development Consultant (5/2017-7/2017)

Collaborated on a curriculum development project for VIPKID online English school.

- Worked collaboratively with school Academic Department and management to reorganize and redevelop the VIPKID curriculum into a format more accessible and comprehensible for parents.
- Helped to design and develop aspects of the curriculum including: level-based format, level goals, target language and grammar, and reading passages.

First Leap English School, Beijing, China

Senior English Teacher (10/2015 - 10/2016)

Provided English language instruction to youth ages 3 to 12 as part of an after-school program.

• Taught twenty-one classes per week spanning a range of subject areas.

- Periodically conducted demonstration classes with prospective students and their families to grow school enrollment.
- Scheduled classes for the school's foreign instructors and communicated with parents about the specific needs of their children.

Concinnate Solutions, LLC

Research Intern (1/2015-9/2015)

Provide industry research support to client delivery teams performing management consulting engagements to commercial and public sector clients.

Wegmans Food Market

Prepared Seafood Cook – (5/2013 – 9/2015)

Lead cook responsible for food preparation to order at in-store seafood bar. Work as part of a team to provide excellent customer service by creating an inviting and responsive dining environment.

Seafood Bar Server/Bartender – (5/2012 – 8/2012)

Responsible for order taking, preparing food and drinks, serving customers, and accepting payments.

Crossroads United Methodist Church

ESL Instructor (9/2014-12/2014)

Class instructor for English as a Second Language program delivered to Spanish speaking adults in the local community.

EDUCATION

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA. BA, International Studies with a Spanish Minor.

ABOUT ME

I enjoy traveling, reading, and physical fitness. I am a self-starter with a strong desire to succeed in all my endeavors.

I have successfully navigated the process of relocating to a foreign country without knowing anyone or the local language. This experience has helped me to grow personally and professionally and become more self-reliant and resourceful.